<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MozammelHaque.com</title><link>https://mozammelhaque.com/</link><description>Recent content on MozammelHaque.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 13:47:44 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mozammelhaque.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting new Mac for development</title><link>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2022-07-18-setting-new-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 13:47:44 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2022-07-18-setting-new-mac/</guid><description>
For VSCode: https://fireship.io/courses/vscode-tricks/basics-settings/ For zsh: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEOqiyxx16c</description></item><item><title>Moving On to New Challenges</title><link>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2015-06-17-moving-new-challenges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 14:38:57 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2015-06-17-moving-new-challenges/</guid><description>
It was not an easy decision – specially when you spend a major part of your life building a company, when your boss becomes not only your friend but also your life mentor, and when you realize that you have a brotherly bond with your colleagues which you never really planned for. But it had to happen one day, and for me that day starts from July 1st, 2015. After devoting 7+ years of my life to Vantage Labs, I’m finally moving on and joining a promising Silicon Valley based startup from next month.</description></item><item><title>Excerpts From Agile Coaching</title><link>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2009-11-11-excerpts-from-agile-coaching/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 20:34:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2009-11-11-excerpts-from-agile-coaching/</guid><description>
Sharing some quotes from the book which I found interesting: Agile Coaching
When a company is in the middle of a reorganization, then people are more focused on keeping their jobs rather than becoming Agile. We would advise against coaching while this is going on because the pressure on the team will be too distracting, and you will probably be wasting your time. To help Agile teams improve, you need to work with the individuals in the team.</description></item><item><title>Full Team Focusing on Single vs Different Stories</title><link>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2009-04-07-single-vs-different-stories/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 20:32:01 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2009-04-07-single-vs-different-stories/</guid><description>
It may be ideal to have your Scrum team focus on a single story first, complete it with compliance of their definition of done, and then move on to the next story, but in practice we are yet to achieve it. What we have found works best for us is we work like small surgical teams where one developer is assigned the chief responsibility of a surgeon for a story and another (or more) developer is tagged along with him as copilot/assistant.</description></item><item><title>No Priorities Set Before Sprint Starts?</title><link>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2009-03-08-no-priorities-before-sprint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 14:38:57 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://mozammelhaque.com/posts/2009-03-08-no-priorities-before-sprint/</guid><description>
You ask the team what’s most important for the product, plan your sprint accordingly, write down the stories and start your sprint!
In an idle world, you are suppose to have your prioritized product backlog ready before your sprint planning meeting. But it may happen that you have a lousy product owner who forgets to update the backlog, or may be she is sick and couldn’t work on it before your next sprint planning.</description></item></channel></rss>